Movies were his passion. Women were his inspiration.
Angora sweaters were his weakness.
Ed Wood is a comedy, drama, history film directed by Tim Burton.
The mostly true story of the legendary "worst director of all time", who, with the help of his
strange friends, filmed countless B-movies without ever becoming famous or successful.
Ed Wood, played by Johnny Depp.
Bela Lugosi, played by Martin Landau.
Dolores Fuller, played by Sarah Jessica Parker.
Kathy O'Hara, played by Patricia Arquette.
Criswell, played by Jeffrey Jones.
Reverend Lemon, played by G. D. Spradlin.
Ed Wood is a 1994 American biographical comedy-drama film directed and produced by
Tim Burton and starring Johnny Depp as the eponymous cult filmmaker.
The film concerns the period in Wood's life when he made his best-known films as well
as his relationship with actor Bela Lugosi, played by Martin Landau.
Sarah Jessica Parker, Patricia Arquette, Jeffrey Jones, Lisa
Marie, and Bill Murray are among the supporting cast.
The film was conceived by writers Scott Alexander and Larry Karaszewski.
Alexander first proposed it as a documentary, when he was a
student at the USC School of Cinematic Arts.
Years later, irritated at being thought of solely as writers for family films with their work on Problem Child (1990) and
its 1991 sequel, Alexander and Karaszewski struck a deal with Burton and Denise Di Novi to produce Ed Wood.
Initially, Michael Lehmann was chosen to direct the project, but due to scheduling conflicts with his work on the
film Airheads (1994), he had to vacate the director's position which was taken over by Tim Burton.
Ed Wood was originally in development at Columbia Pictures, but the studio put the
film in "turnaround" over Burton's decision to shoot in black-and-white.
Ed Wood was taken to Walt Disney Studios, which produced the
film through its Touchstone Pictures banner.
The film proved financially unsuccessful, returning only $13.8 million against an $18 million budget, but was met with critical acclaim upon release, with particular praise for Depp and Landau's
performances and the makeup, and won two Academy Awards: Best Supporting Actor for Landau and Best Makeup for Rick Baker (who designed Landau's prosthetic makeup), Ve Neill and Yolanda Toussieng.
The film is now considered to be a cult classic and one of Burton's best works.
The film explores themes of individual, taxi, fortune
teller, transsexuality, transvestite.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.